Surekha K G

Bangalore, Karnataka

7893977337

surekhagurumurthy@gmail.com

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/surekhakg/



A decade+ years of diversified experience in visionary and strategic Sales leader in BFSI / NBFC in direct sales and marketing dedicated to organization growth with business objectives.

Specializing in the intricacies of B2B dynamics with 2+ years as HRBP partner with varied experience from onboarding to retention Talent Management, PMS, Employee Relations, Organizational Development, and stakeholder management. Known for challenging the status quo in creating practical & focused strategies and solutions with the business to address challenges. I am committed to building strong partnerships with business leaders, ensuring HR practices enhance productivity and contribute to the overall success of the company.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Human Resources Business Partner ElasticRun - October 2021 to Dec 2023

HR Operation: Managed complete employee life cycle from onboarding to exit of people, process, Employee engagement, building trusted relationships with employees/stakeholders and on-time completion of important employee life cycle milestones for B2B Rural, E-commerce, Velocity, and expansion verticals.

Business Consultant: "Edufin" - Education Financing for parents and schools from November 2020 to September 2021.

Business Consultant: From Jan 2019 to September 2020 "Inner Treasure - Wunderfit" Direct Selling Firm - Health, Wellness products.

Shiksha Financial Services Pvt Ltd

August 2017 -- January 2019

State Business Head - Karnataka

- Have set up the entire business process for the state-initiated business in 5 new locations as per the business plan.
- Created a strategic roadmap and execution plan for the acquisition of new locations/clients in line with the overall organizational objectives.
- Lead a team of 7 District /Sales Executives sourcing unsecured and secured loans -Initiated Student loan sourcing from July, Recruited, Trained, and mentored Sales Executives. Achieved sales volume of >7 crores in a span of 8 months.



PERSONAL INFORMATION

DOB - 24th Jan 1977 Father's Name - K S Gurumurthachari Status - Single

EDUCATION

- PGDBA: Bangalore University
- MA (English): Bangalore University
- BA. Arts: NMKRV, Bangalore University
- PUC: Bishop Cotton Women's Christian
- SSLC: St. Meera's High School

SKILLS & PROFICIENCIES

- Sales and Marketing
- Business Analytics
- Employee Engagement
- Stakeholder Management
- Team Development
- Client Servicing
- Strategize
- Organize and Coaching

COMPETENCIES

- Leadership Skills
- Talent Management
- Team Management
- Drive Results
- **Business Acumen**
- Market Research
- Planning & Organizing

LANGUAGES

Kannada, Hindi, Telugu & Tamil

EXPERTISE

- Expert in core sales and marketing, HR operations, and employee engagement
- Possess in-depth practical knowledge of sales, operations, banking, insurance, and business analytics
- Handle the sales division with the aim of fulfilling the organization's vision
- Demonstrate strong leadership, reasoning, negotiation, and communication skills
- Meet deadlines and deliver breakthrough results in compliance with organizational culture, policy, and process
- Skilfully hire and source the right talent and manage a team
- Confident, hardworking, and adaptable to change management

ACHIEVEMENTS & CERTIFICATE

- Awarded Best Bancassurance Officer for demonstrating teamwork and coordination at ABN AMRO Bank
- Achieved Top Agency Manager status for generating maximum profit at MetLife
- Recognized as Consistent Top
 Performing Branch Manager for Region at
 Reliance Life Insurance
- Honored as Best New Employee of the Year for showing commitment, responsibility, and client service at Tupperware
- Completed Fundamentals of Human Resource course from Alison
- Obtained a Diploma in Human Resources from Alison
- Certified as CHRBP from Middle Earth
- Completed Talent Management online course by Grate Learning and enhanced HR skills

DECLARATION

I affirm that the information given in this resume is accurate and complete to the best of my knowledge and belief.

ICFAI group

Jan 2016 - May 2017

Regional Manager Corporate Accounts - Corporate Account Management operations for promoting ICFAI FLP programs to identified corporates across the region

Tupperware

Oct 2010 - Dec 2015

Associate Sales Development Manager - Regional Head

As ASDM heading Andhra Region – leading 6 Distributorships with 25 Executive Managers, 450 Managers, and 15000 consultants. Directly responsible for consistent growth of distributorships through effective organization, development of executive managers into future business leaders through coaching and mentoring, training managers for business development through weekly workshops and half-yearly conferences, and enhancing the earnings of consultants through the implementation of weekly and monthly promotional events.

Reliance Life Insurance Metlife India Insurance Co ABN AMRO BANK

Nov 2008 - Aug 2010 Dec 2007 - Sep 2008 July 2006 - Sep 2007

Branch/Agency/Banca Manager

- Accountable for running the branch as a profit centre for the company.
- To achieve branch target through the team of Sales Managers, Advisors & Agency Managers
- Responsible for recruitment of financial consultants to agreed profiles and within the stipulated time frame so as to achieve Business plan targets for the branch.
- Plan and achieve branch business targets in the area of number of financial advisors, productivity, new premium, and persistency of business.
- Scan the market for emerging opportunities, presence of competition, etc.
- Draw elaborate plans for the recruitment of financial advisors, their training, and mentoring.
- Establish good working habits for the sales field force undertake productivity improvement drives,
- Facilitating business generation from the Unsecured Channels (GoldCards, Cards-DST & Personal Loans) and the Mortgage Channel
- Co-ordination with the Aviva Team for the life business and the ICICLL ombard Team for the non-life business

Global Capital & Property service Finasset Resources

Dec 2005 - Jun 2006 July 1997 - Aug 2005

Business Partner

Worked in as a Direct Sales Agency of American Express Bank, ICICI Bank Ltd, Standard Chartered Bank & ING Vysya Bank Ltd. Held various positions and various products:

- Sept 1999 to August 2005 Director (Marketing)
- July 1998 to August 1999 Marketing Manager
- July 1997 to June 1998- Marketing Executive

Shelters - DST of CitiBank - Marketing Executive and Customer Support for Mortgage products Jan 1997 - June 1997

• Life Insurance Advisor - Om Kotak Mahindra Life Insurance 2002 - 2005